<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>J. Alonso Guerra</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on J. Alonso Guerra</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 10:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mastering Worker Pools in Go: A Practical Guide</title><link>/post/2026-02-14-golang-worker-pools/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/post/2026-02-14-golang-worker-pools/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Go for any amount of time, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably reached a point where spinning up a goroutine per task starts to feel wrong. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re hitting API rate limits, exhausting database connections, or just watching your memory usage climb. That&amp;rsquo;s where &lt;strong&gt;worker pools&lt;/strong&gt; come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A worker pool is a concurrency pattern where a fixed number of goroutines (workers) process tasks from a shared queue. It gives you &lt;strong&gt;controlled parallelism&lt;/strong&gt; — the ability to do many things at once without doing &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; at once.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;J. Alonso Guerra&lt;/strong&gt;, a backend engineer from Colombia who&amp;rsquo;s been building distributed systems and cloud-native applications with &lt;strong&gt;Go&lt;/strong&gt; for the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about designing systems that handle real scale — from messaging platforms processing millions of daily interactions to billing engines with real-time event processing. I enjoy the challenge of making things fast, reliable, and elegant under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what-i-do" id=what-i-do&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What I do&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-i-do" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I currently work as a &lt;strong&gt;Senior Backend Engineer&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href="https://ipcom.ai/"&gt;Ipcom&lt;/a&gt;, where I design event-driven architectures on GCP, build real-time reporting systems, and lead the backend development of AI-powered voicebot platforms. Before that, I worked on microservices modernization for &lt;a href="https://amaris.com/"&gt;Falabella&lt;/a&gt; (one of Latin America&amp;rsquo;s largest retailers) and built digital security platforms at &lt;a href="https://virtualpadlocks.com/"&gt;Virtual Padlock&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>/archives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>